Thomas Brown

https://www.tsbrown.net

www.linkedin.com/in/tomsouthwellbrown

SUMMARY

Statistician in the pharmaceutical industry specialising in the development of data driven approaches in clinical development. Recognised expert in R and interactive application development for data analysis and visualisation. Part of pioneering team developing machine learning algorithms for early phase research.

EXPERIENCE

Statistician

Veramed (September 2016 - Present)

- Developing machine learning algorithms to predict clinical outcomes for patients
- Designing and analysing clinical trials in immunology and neurology
- Created numerous statistical simulations to assess operating characteristics of a study
- Presenting statistical analyses and concepts to non-statistical colleagues
- Recognised as the in-house expert in R and data visualisation

Sales and Membership / Sponsorship and Advertising Assistant

University of Sydney Union (February 2014 – September 2015)

- Responsible for a membership program consisting of over 15,000 students
- Managed a team to run events promoting membership to the University of Sydney Union
- Developed and Maintained client relationships for a multi-channel advertising program
- Assisted with the management and execution of on-campus projects

EDUCATION

Master of Science (Medical Statistics)

London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine, University of London (2015 – 2016)

Bachelor of Arts (Honours) (English)

University of Sydney (2011 - 2014)

Exchange Student

University of Leeds (2012 - 2013)

SKILLS

R

- Extensive experience and expertise using R for data management and statistical analysis
- Lead developer for several R Shiny applications used for client projects
- Regarded as the principal in house expert at Veramed for R

Python

- Developed machine learning algorithms and performed exploratory analyses in Python
- Experience with common scientific packages including numpy, pandas, scikit-learn, and keras

SQL

- Write SQL queries to extract data from external databases
- Use SQL syntax within SAS for manipulating clinical trial data

Data Visualisation

• Developed both static and interactive publication quality graphics for presenting to both statistical and non-statistical audiences.

Data Manipulation

• Able to handle unstructured and messy data to develop 'analysis ready' datasets in multiple formats

Self-Learning

• Since completing a MSc, have independently pursued and successfully completed numerous educational courses. These include Stanford Online's Statistical Learning Course, nearly 50 courses on DataCamp, and frequently attend meetups and conferences for statistics and data science.

Machine Learning

- Built multiple algorithms for both supervised learning and deep learning scenarios.
- Acted as a consultant for clients regarding the design and implementation of machine learning algorithms.

Statistical Modelling

• Performed statistical modelling to analyses clinical outcomes and assess product efficacy. Experienced with Bayesian methodology and advanced simulation techniques

Experimental Design

- Designed multiple early phase exploratory clinical studies to determine drug efficacy.
- Create proof of concept studied and analyses to inform future business portfolio decisions

REFERENCES

Available on Request